In this section we're going to discuss a very important exam topic.
We've already talked a little bit about it in previous sections but now we're going to get into the
very specifics.
Well what is the topic.
Project environments.
Remember the environment that you operate in as a project manager affects how you get to manage that
project.
So we need to look at the project environments.
So some new terms for you are going to look at enterprise environmental factors and organizational process
assets that these are things that will be an input to a lot of processes and then you'll update them
as your project creates more information.
So we'll talk about Enterprise environmental factors in organizational process assets.
You can abbreviate those like I do we'll call the ETF and O.P..
So that's what that means.
But you'll pick that up in no time.
Also look at processes policies and procedures.
So what are the processes that you do in your organization.
What are the policies that you restrict or control how you do that process and what procedures you have
to follow as a PM Where do you work as specific to your organization.
We'll look at organizational systems and frameworks the management elements that affect how you manage
your project.
And then a really important topic I hinted about it a little bit earlier.
It's organizational structure types.
It's how has the organization structure like lines of business by projects by different departments.
So the organizational structure type affects how much power you get as a project manager.
So I hinted at this a little bit earlier.
Well this is where we're going to get into these different structure types.
And then you will do an assignment about defining these different organizational types are really important
you complete that because you need to know the structure types who you're exempt you need to know how
do you operate as a project manager in any given structure.
And so right now if you don't work in that particular structure you can see how that will be a challenge
on your exam if you don't know the nuances of that structure.
OK let's hop in here and knock out the section about Project environments.
Let's get going right now.